Return to Jurassic Park is a documentary film directed by Laurent Bouzereau.
A multi-part documentary about the making of the Jurassic Park trilogy.
Each part walks through the making of part of one of the films, including the hurricane during the shooting of the
first film, and how advances in CGI for Jurassic Park helped change the world of special effects forever.
All interviews for these retrospective documentaries come with comments from Spielberg, Johnston,
Neill, Dern, Goldblum, the effects crews, the child actors, and Peter Stormare.
This documentary is broken into six parts: Dawn of a New Era (25 min), Making Prehistory (20 min), The Next Step in
Evolution (15 min), Finding the Lost World (28 min), Something Survived (16 min), and The Third Adventure (25 min).
Self, played by Steven Spielberg.
Self, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Self, played by Sam Neill.
Self, played by Laura Dern.
Self (archive footage), played by Fay Wray.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Crichton.
Jurassic World is a 2015 American science fiction action film directed by Colin Trevorrow, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Rick Jaffa, Amanda Silver, and Derek Connolly from a story by Jaffa and Silver.
It is the first installment in the Jurassic World series and the fourth installment
overall in the Jurassic Park franchise, following Jurassic Park III (2001).
It stars an ensemble cast including Chris Pratt, Bryce Dallas Howard, Vincent D'Onofrio, Ty Simpkins, Nick
Robinson, Omar Sy, BD Wong, and Irrfan Khan; Wong reprised his role from the original Jurassic Park film.
Set 22 years after the events of Jurassic Park, the film takes place on the same
fictional island of Isla Nublar, located off the Pacific coast of Costa Rica.
A successful theme park of cloned dinosaurs, dubbed Jurassic World,  has operated
on the island for years, bringing John Hammond's dream to fruition.
The park plunges into chaos when a transgenic dinosaur
escapes from its enclosure and goes on a rampage.
Universal Pictures intended to begin production of a fourth Jurassic Park film in 2004 for a mid-2005
release, but the project lingered in development hell while the script underwent several revisions.
Following a suggestion from executive producer Steven Spielberg, writers Jaffa
and Silver explored the idea of a functional dinosaur park.
Once Trevorrow was hired as director in 2013 he followed the same
idea while developing a new script with Connolly.
Filming lasted from April to August 2014 in Louisiana and Hawaii.
Like the previous films, the dinosaurs were created by Lucasfilm's Industrial Light &
Magic using CGI and by Legacy Effects using life-sized animatronics.
Production was completed in May 2015.
Jurassic World premiered at Le Grand Rex in Paris on May 29, 2015, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 12, by Universal Pictures.
It received generally favorable reviews, with some critics
considering it to be the best Jurassic Park sequel.
On release, it set several box office records, including for the largest opening weekend, both domestically and worldwide, and ultimately grossed $1.6 billion worldwide, becoming the
second-highest-grossing film of 2015, the third highest-grossing film of all time, the highest-grossing in the Jurassic Park series and the highest-grossing film released by Universal.
Three sequels have been released: Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom (2018),
Jurassic World Dominion (2022), and Jurassic World Rebirth (2025).
The film explores themes of behind the scenes, special
effects, dinosaur, practical special effects.